

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

970 Corte Madera, Apt 209, Sunnyvale, 94085

□ (+1) 650-307-3844 | 🗷 andres@otarola.me | 😭 otarola.me | 🖸 aotarola | 🛅 aotarolaalvarado

### **Summary**

Software Engineer with 7+ years of experience, I have worked with Nodejs, Ruby on Rails, PHP, Python and Django framework for the most part of my career.

Currently, I'm working at Groupon as a Software Engineer involved in the team in charge of maintaining and delivery solutions as well as new features to the login/signup and checkout application of the platform.

A bit about myself; I'm a big fan of Service Oriented Systems and Continuous Integration, I like dynamic languages, distributed version control systems like GIT (I love Github BTW), cool editors like VS Code (but, VIM will always be my prefered one!). I also play well with Linux / OS X, Splunk, Wavefront, ELK, and intermediate sysadmin tools (enough to help myself to debug/restore a running app). If I cannot solve an issue, I know how to gather enough data and ask the right person the right question to unblock myself.

I'm very passionate in the things I do, especially if the task is challenging.

I like to create things and/or use the tools/libraries the right way but I'm also aware of delivering badass software at the committed date is at the same level of importance!

And of course I like to learn new stuff / tech!, and finally, I love green tea.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Groupon Palo Alto, United States

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul. 2015 - Present

- Migrated the checkout and user auth flow out of a monolothic app to a microservice oriented architecture that runs small specialized Node.js
   apps
- Migrated International web platforms to US platforms
- Refactored confirmation/receipt page UX-wise CSS and JS was remade
- Implemented Apple Pay and PayPal for checkout web client for desktop and touch
- Migrated checkout and user session web apps logging searches from splunk to ELK
- Integrated ELK searches into wavefront
- Led touch redesign project for confirmation page frontend stack was redux and preact
- Migrated integration tests from PhantomJS to Headless Chrome on Dockerized Alpine images for Jenkins CI
- Built and led magic link Frontend implementation as an alternate authentication method
- In charge of performance reporting and improvements for login web app
- Migrated on-prem login app to AWS

Needish Santiago, Chile

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2012 - Jul. 2015

- Developed solutions for the web platform, tech used was PHP and CakePHP.
- In charge of email deliverability with Sendgrid and ReturnPath.
- Migrated user accounts from EMEA platform to Needish platform, worked on a ETL to achive that.

Dreamside Iquique, Chile

• Developed a service that calculates monthly revenue of the company (for "Teck" Mining Company)

- Deliver solutions such as fixes and new features to their legacy systems, written in ASP

Meaculpa's Liquor Store Chain

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FREELANCER

Iquique, Chile Mar. 2008 - May. 2008

Sep. 2011 - Mar. 2012

• Developed REST synchronization API for distributed POS management.

Developed administration web application system, written in Python using Django.

Universidad Arturo Prat Iquique, Chile

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - INTERN

• Created a web portal for alumni, that displays their class information. Tech used: PHP and ORACLE

Jan. 2008 - Feb. 2008

# Education

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **UNAP(Universidad Arturo Prat)**

Iquique, Chile

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2004 - 2009